

CONTACT

PHONE: +91-9753750955

SKYPE: ambujdubey or ambujdubey@outlook.in

WEBSITE:

https://ambujbpl.github.io/

GITHUB:

(https://github.com/ambujbpl)

EMAIL:

ambujdubey89@gmail.com

Linkedin

https://in.linkedin.com/in/ambujdubey-2923b456)

AMBUJ DUBEY

PROFILE

Dedicated and efficient full stack developer with 4.8+ years of experience in application layers, presentation layers, and databases. Certified in both Front-end and Back-end technologies. Having hands-on experience designing, developing, and implementing applications and solutions using a range of technologies and programming languages. Played major role with technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize CSS, ReactJS, React Native, NodeJs, Strapi, EJS, Php Core, MongoDB, MySQL and MsSQL.

I prefer challenges that require me to work on projects in which I have to work outside my comfort zone and knowledge set. Learning new languages and development techniques are important for me as well as my organizations growth. I worked with AWS, Azure, Heroku, Digital Ocean and others cloud services skillfully.

EXPERIENCES

Sr. Software Engineer at IndiaNIC Infotech Limited Ahmedabad

2021-Now

- Working as a Sr. Software Engineer.
- Collaborates with development team which includes Product Manager, Software Engineer and Quality Assurance team to identifying software problems, testing methods, and best solutions.
- Object-Oriented Analysis.

Full-Stack Developer at Logikview Analytics Indore

2019-2021

- Collaborates with development team which includes Product Manager, Software Engineer and Quality Assurance team to identifying software problems, testing methods, and best solutions.
- Developed full-stack applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.
- Integrated app-based solutions with databases, file systems, and cloud-based systems.
- Object-Oriented Analysis.

Junior Full Stack Developer at Ideata Analytics 2018-2019 Indore

- Developed software applications with technologies like Nodejs, Strapi, Express, is and integration with REST APIs for ADFS services, live tracking application and other services.
- Managed, optimized, and updated databases as necessary.
- Collaborates with development team and created testing methods.
- Object-Oriented Analysis and Relational Database Systems.
- Testing the designed unit test case.

EDUCATION C-DAC

Hyderabad 2016 74.00 %

Master of Technology OIST Bhopal / RGPV Bhopal 2013 - 2015 86.00 %

Bachelor of Engineering

TIEIT BHOPAL / RGPV Bhopal 2007 - 2011 70.59 %

Higher Secondary

Government School For Excellence, Hoshangabad(MP) 2007 77.40 %

High School

Government School For Excellence, Hoshangabad(MP) 2005 82.20 %

Software Developer at Greenticks Bhopal

- Worked as a Full stack software developer.
- Provided expert technical advice and guidance on projects.
- Created the architecture for software also provided hosting solution and strategize with clients to create software that solves business problems.

Software Developer at Mobigesture Hyderabad

2016

 Worked as front end developer with special expertise in Responsive Web Design by using Bootstrap3 framework.

SKILL SET

Technical skills - Web Performance, Responsive Web Design, Automated Testing.

Programming languages - JavaScript, Basic C language.

Frontend Technologies - HTML, CSS, Bootstrap framework, Ajax, JQuery (JavaScript library), AngularJS (limited), ReactJS, NextJS, ReactNative, Expo, Bower, Webpack, Json..

Backend Technologies - Node.js, Express.js (Server-Side JavaScript Framework), Strapi, PHP.

Database Technologies - MySQL (RDBMS), MongoDB.

Operating System - macOS, Linux, Windows Operating System.

Tools Used - WebStorm, Sublime, Atom, Eclipse, GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket, Visual Studio Code, DbVisualizer, FileZilla, Postman, Mongodb Compass, OpenVPN, Forticlient.

Communication Tools - Trello, Clockify, Dropbox, Pivotal Tracker, Slack, Google Drive, Mattermost, EchoHQ, Discord, NPM, Yarn & NVM.

Others Skills – Single sign out (oAuth), Google Authentication, Payment gatway (stripe), Webhooks implementation, MLab, Heroku Platform, Web-Hosting, Mocha Unit test, Database Caching, Database Catalog, Redis, Wordpress CMS Hosting, Nodejs Monolithic and Microservices based Architecture.

PROJECTS

| Project Title: | Game reporting |
|----------------------|---|
| Duration: | 8 Months |
| Technology: | React Native, MSSQL, EXPO, Android App, IOS App, Azure. SSO and SMS API integration |
| Project Description: | This is a mobile application for reporting a bird hunting game. |
| Role: | Full stack software developer. |

2018

LANGUAGES

English (Professional) Hindi (Native)

GENERAL PROFICIENCIES

Creative Team Work Willingness To Learn Dedication in work

HOBBIES

Internet Surfing Sports Activities Learn New Technologies

Personal Profile

Father's Name : Mr. Shravan Dubey Mother's Name : Mrs. Kalpana Dubey

Date of Birth : 06-08-1989 Nationality : Indian Permanent Address : 20-A

Sachchidanand Nagar, BHEL, Bhopal

(M.P.)

| Project Title: | Bail Management system (BMS) |
|----------------------|--|
| Duration: | Aug 2018(Present) |
| Technology: | HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, MSSQL Server, Bootstrap, DataTable, NodeJS, Strapi. Azure, Azure Function, Scheduled Notification, Corp Authentication |
| Project Description: | Tool provides platform as a single point of access to Datasets in open format published by Ministries/Departments. |
| Role: | Full stack software developer. |

| Project Title: | Open Data portal |
|----------------------|------------------------------------|
| Duration: | Aug 2018(Present) |
| Technology: | HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, |
| | MSSQL Server, Bootstrap, |
| | DataTable, NodeJS, Strapi. |
| Project Description: | Tool provides platform as a single |
| | point of access to Datasets in |
| | open format published by |
| | Ministries/Departments |
| Role: | Full stack software developer. |

| Project Title: | BDA project |
|----------------------|--|
| Duration: | 2 years |
| Technology: | HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, Java, AngularJS, AWS Redshift Nodejs, MySQL, Bootstrap, JUnit test, D3 JS, C3 js , Echarts JS, Apache Spark, AWS RDS, Shell Script, Data Visualizations, Heroku. |
| Project Description: | Tool provides an easy to use analytics platform for users to ingest, clean, prepare and analyze data with visualizations, and help to create reports. |
| Role: | Full stack software developer. |

| Project Title: | Track And Trace Project |
|----------------------|--|
| Duration: | 2 years |
| Technology: | HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, MySQL, Bootstrap, DataTable, NodeJS, Java, Scheduled Jobs (CronJobs), excel sheets, Node- Mailer, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, Nginx. |
| Project Description: | Tool provides higher level of tracking system of individual shipments and creates a detailed dashboard also send alert when status of shipment gets changed. |
| Role: | Full stack software developer. |

| Project Title: | Mobibuzz project |
|----------------------|--|
| Duration: | 4 Months |
| Technology: | HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, MongoDB, Node.js, Bootstrap. |
| Project Description: | This project helps to track employee login, logout time, employee detailed profile, it consist Leave Management system and it also track employee status and company events. |
| Role: | Front end developer. |

| Project Title: | KnoahsARK 360 |
|----------------------|---|
| Duration: | 5 Months |
| Project Description: | KnoahsARK enables client to manage the entire customer contact center environment by integrating locations, staff, departments, tools, data points and processes to give you one view towards making better |
| | decisions |
| Role: | Front end developer. |

| Project Title: | VHT project |
|----------------------|--|
| Duration: | 7 Months |
| Project Description: | VHT use to recognized the severity of customer frustration in relation to delivering exceptional customer service. This led to inventing a patented solution, VHT Callback, which eliminated wait time while increasing customer satisfaction. |
| Role: | Developer (Language Method and grammar Developer, tested method by using JUnit test cases, Automate entire development by using Cucumber and ruby and run it into Jenkins). |

| Project Title: | ITI Jobs Portal project |
|----------------------|--|
| Duration: | 2 Months |
| Technology: | HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, Nodejs, MySQL, DOM, AJAX, |
| | Json, Bootstrap4. |
| Project Description: | Tool provides ITI related |
| | database. Here, users can |
| | manage, store, share and |
| | disseminate information about |
| | placement, ITI collages, and its |
| | having high level monitoring. |
| Role: | Full stack software developer |
| | (End to end product |
| | development with Responsive |
| | Web Design by using Bootstrap4 |
| | framework). |

| Project Title: | Greenticks project |
|----------------------|---|
| Duration: | 2 Months |
| Technology: | HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, Nodejs, MySQL, MongoDB, DOM, AJAX, Json, Bootstrap 4, Mocha unit test, Webpack, Wordpress4.7, MLab, Heroku. |
| Project Description: | Tool provides computer based online exam details along with Invigilator details and track daily report. |
| Role: | Full stack software developer. |

| Project Title: | Aerotic Project |
|-----------------------------|--|
| Duration: | 2020(present) |
| Technology: | HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, |
| | Core PHP, MySQL, DOM, AJAX, |
| | Json, Bootstrap 4. |
| | |
| Project Description: | Tool provides product details and also generate daily invoices. It also provide reminder for the customer. |
| Project Description: Role: | and also generate daily invoices. It also provide reminder for the |

| Project Title: | Harshuj |
|----------------------|---|
| Duration: | 2020(present) |
| Technology: | HTML, CSS, Java Script, JQuery, Core PHP, MySQL, Composer, DOM, AJAX, Json, Materialize- CSS, Digital-Ocean. |
| Project Description: | Tool provides one destination for many applications like contacts, reminders, to-do-list, useful weblinks, notes, feedback etc. |
| Role: | Full stack software developer. |

SKILLS

